Hello!
大家好
And welcome to a special children in need minisode of Doctor Who!
欢迎来到神秘博士 Children in Need 迷你特别篇
And not just any minisode,
这不是一般的迷你集
that's just what we call them,
虽然我们这样叫它
this is a prequel to the Christmas special.
它其实还是今年圣诞特辑的前传
Now, if you remember,
现在 还记得吗
When last scene the doctor said goodbye to his best friend Rory
在上一集里 博士告别了他最好的朋友罗伊
and to Amelia Pond, the woman who will never be replaced in his hearts
以及艾米莉亚·庞德——在他心中永远不可替代的女人
Hi.
你好
Oh don't worry, she won't be watching.
别担心 她看不见的
Of course not.
当然
She's in L.A.
她在洛杉矶呢
Exactly.
没错
Roll the minisode.
播放迷你集
Do we really call them that?
咱们真的这么叫它吗
Yeah, minisode, that's what they called that's a cool name.
对呀 它们就叫"迷你集" 多酷的名字
Roll the minisode.
播放迷你集
伟大的侦探
In London in the time of Queen Victoria,
在维多利亚女王时代的伦敦
there were many tales of a remarkable personage known as the Great Detective.
流传着一位被誉为"伟大的侦探"的杰出人物的诸多传说
I refer, of course, to
当然了 我指的是
Madame Vastra,
瓦斯特拉夫人
the lizard woman of Paternoster Row
帕诺斯特街的蜥蜴女
and her extraordinary adventures,
和她非凡的冒险
her beautiful assistant, Jenny Flint,
她美丽的助手 珍妮·弗林特
and their mysterious henchman, Strax,
还有他们神秘的追随者 斯扎克斯
whose countenance was too abominable to be photographed.
它的面容实在是过于可憎 不宜登报
What?
怎么了
There are also accounts of a fourth member of the Paternoster Gang,
帕诺斯特街小队还有第四名成员
a shadowy figure
一个行踪不定的人物
whose assistance was only sought
只有在最危急的情况下
in the direst emergencies.
他们才会去寻求他的帮助
I'm so glad you came.
很高兴你来了
We have news,
我们有一些新闻
I think, of particular interest to you.
我觉得 你会感兴趣的
There was a meteor shower in the southwest,
西南地区有一场流星雨
unexpected timing and density.
发生的时机和密度都出人意料
I've calculated there is a 34% chance it is the result of alien intervention.
据我计算有 34% 的可能性是外星人造成的
Twenty four percent.
24%
Well, they could just be meteors
好吧 可能只是流星而已
but it is worth looking in to.
但是也值得调查一下
There is a very pleasant tea room in the area.
那附近有一个不错的茶室
Also, there's a Professor Erasmus Pink
对了 有位伊拉斯谟·平克教授
who's claiming he's going to split the world open with a giant drill
他说要用一个巨大的钻头 打穿地壳最薄的部分
through the thinnest part of the Earth's crust.
把地球撕裂成两半
I think we should investigate.
我觉得我们应该展开调查
I mean, he doesn't actually have a giant drill,
虽然吧 他其实并没有巨大的钻头
and he's not really a professor,
也不是真正的教授
and he was a bit drunk at the time and singing a bit,
而且他当时是喝了点酒 还在唱歌
but you know it is never too early to investigate a drill.
但是调查钻头这种事还是...尽早比较好
I've declared war on the moon.
我向月球宣战了
Do be quiet, Strax.
安静点儿 斯扎克斯.
Too long the moon has hung unmonitored and unsuspected in the sky.
月球长期处于不被监视和无人怀疑的状态
It has gained an enormous tactical advantage.
它已经取得了巨大的战术优势
There's no one living there.
那上面没有人
Then it is clearly time to act.
那么这正是行动的时机
They won't suspect a thing.
他们根本不会起疑
Who won't suspect a thing?
谁不会起疑
Moon Knights.
月亮骑士
Why do you keep doing this?
你们为什么一直找我
What is the point?
有意义吗
I have told you.
我已经说过了
I keep telling you,
我说了无数遍了
I don't do this any more.
我不干了
I've retired.
我退休了
There's a man on Praed Street with an invisible wife.
普拉德街有个男人 他有个隐形的老婆
Maybe he just doesn't have a wife.
也许他只是没有老婆
You're wasting my time.
你们在浪费时间
Merry Christmas!
圣诞快乐
I think he means it.
我觉得他是认真的
Yes, my dear,
是的 亲爱的
I rather think he does.
看来确实如此
Damn moon.
该死的月亮
There you go, the doctor has retired.
看呐 博士退休了
This Christmas the earth will face terrible terrible danger.
今年圣诞节 地球会面临非常可怕的危险
But, as all humanity hangs in the balance,
但是 当全人类命悬一线的时候
will anyone be able to persuade the doctor to save the day?
有人能够说服博士拯救世界吗
Yes.
会有
Well, so much for dramatic tension.
哎呀 这样就没有戏剧张力了
Blimey! Jenna.
服了你了 珍娜
Right, see you later for the very first showing of the Christmas trailer.
好的 我们在圣诞特辑预告片首映后再见
See you later.
再见